<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[1]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[1]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-concept-impact-mid-term-review-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict Sensitivity - Concept to Impact Mid-term Review Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This report offers a mid-term review of the project 'The practice of conflict sensitivity - concept to impact' delivered by a consortium of NGOs in the UK Kenya Sierra Leone and Sri Lanka. It is a developmental review geared towards both confirming progress to date and highlighting areas for further consideration as the project moves forward. In summary the project is found to remain effective efficient and relevant within the constraints it operates under and is considered to be on its way to achieving its goal and purpose. Specific recommendations are summarised in a table at the end of the report. Key issues emerging from the six key elements of the project include the following: Developing a shared definition of conflict sensitivity: appropriate and contextually owned working definitions have been agreed and shared and the process of developing these has been valuable in seeding debate and clarifying thinking within the consortia. The longer-term aim of arriving at one unified definition seems achieveable though is not a current priority. Analysing constraints and barriers to conflict sensitivity: self-assessment processes have been completed and reported in almost all participating agencies and have been highly valued both as sources of baseline information and as learning and influencing processes. Commonalities and differences have emerged which validate the project's starting assumptions about the nature and scale of the task of mainstreaming conflict sensitivity. Limitations in both the assessment tool and the analysis of findings means that there is more work to be done to extract more useful meaningful and operationalisable findings from this aspect of the project. Building capacity for conflict sensitivity: whilst the process of defining change objectives and capacity building plans is still under way in all four countries significant changes have already been made in some participating organisations. Designing and delivering the capacity building work successfully would benefit from more attention to determining the boundaries of conflict sensitivity for the purposes of the project (i.e. where it differs from general 'good practice') and deeper reflection on how organisational change happens: this will allow a more sharply targetted and ultimately impactful strategy to be developed. Documenting and sharing existing practice: the small number of case studies already developed are rather thin and further attention is required to the question of what kind of case study really supports learning and stimulates change in practice. Once this is clear the documentation of cases should be utilised across all programme areas as a mechanism for delivering on the project's learning and influencing objectives. A web-based platform for sharing both within and beyond the project is close to being launched. Testing monitoring and evaluating innovative approaches: at this time conflict analysis work has been done or is under way which will inform the identification and design of pilot initiatives through which innovations will be tried out. Members of the four consortia are keen that participation in these initiatives is project-wide even though only some agencies will be directly managing a pilot project. The pilots will also be a vehicle for developing systems for monitoring and evaluating conflict sensitivity an area in which there is little existing expertise to draw on and therefore this project represents the cutting edge. An experimental learning-by-doing approach to all aspects of this innovation is encouraged with facilitation where required. Advocacy and outreach: this aspect of the work is not yet active beyond some opportunistic outreach to interested organisations. There are concerns and somewhat muddled ideas about what kind of advocacy and outreach the project can do and a reframing of this agenda as 'influencing' is recommended in order to clarify this and manage expectations. The specific target of influencing DFID requires a deepening and expansion of the relationship between the project and DFID and a clarification of expectations and commitments on both sides. The review also considered the management and governance of this project as a consortium highlighting the significant costs involved in functioning this way but suggesting that benefits are now starting to flow which make it worthwhile. The project needs to work on some ongoing issues including: balancing the levels of contribution by different agencies addressing the practical and strategic constraints on deeper participation by member agencies reducing dependence on the project coordinators managing budgetary and financial issues more fluidly enabling more real-time and multi-layered communication across the four consortia setting boundaries to membership of the consortia and handling the North-South dynamics of the project. A concluding suggestion is that the project may benefit from exploring the overlaps and synergies between different elements of the work going forward and some of the recommendations reflect this idea. The final evaluation will be an important opportunity to synthesise and communicate the overall lessons from the project and should be designed to maximise its own value in these terms: therefore a participatory 4-country relatively long term process with external facilitation is recommended.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSC Mid-Term Evaluation Report Final.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[2]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[2]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-emergency-response-guide-annex-1-case-studies]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity in Emergency Response Guide Annex 1: Case Studies]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The cases studies in this Annex are mostly aligned with the sections in the Sphere Project: Humanitarian Charter and Minimum Standards in Disaster Response.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Annex 1 -Case Studies.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[3]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[3]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/terms-reference-research-consultancy-csa-emergencies-learning-review]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Terms of Reference for Research Consultancy CSA in Emergencies Learning Review]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Humanitarian responses to rapid on-set emergencies often represent significant challenges in terms of applying conflict sensitivity. The complexity of the contexts in which these events often occur and the speed in which organizations need to react leave little capacity for sophisticated analysis or training of frontline particularly local staff. In order to maximize effectiveness agencies must be ready to take advantage of opportunities as they arise to integrate conflict sensitivity across their teams and design systems and guidance that can be readily deployed. This needs to be done with an appreciation of the operating constraints presented by the context frequent resource shortfalls and existing commitments to other accountability frameworks and pre-existing emergency response guidelines for surge capacity staff. This review will retrospectively assess the degree to which CSA were explicitly or implicitly carried out in the humanitarian responses led by CARE and CAFOD in Haiti and Pakistan. This reflective exercise will culminate in both agency-specific and sector-wide recommendations being made to ensure greater CSA application in future rapid onset emergency responses. It will build on work undertaken in 2010 by the Conflict Sensitivity Consortium that aims to better understand CSA implications in humanitarian responses when the Consortium produced an internal ‘good enough’ guide that lays out guidance as to how NGO systems and actions can be adapted to improve conflict sensitivity in the first phase (30 days) of an emergency response.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSA_in_Emergencies_Learning_Review.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[4]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[4]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/csc-consortium-proposal]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CSC Consortium Proposal]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Project Summary: The project goal is to ensure greater impact of development and humanitarian assistance through improved and more widespread mainstreaming of conflict sensitive approaches. The purpose is to improve policies and practices that support CSA across a broad network of NGOs local partners and donor agencies. Key outcomes will be: Shared understanding of CSA across a network of international and local development humanitarian and peace building organisations; Lessons and recommendations for mainstreaming effective CSA across a range of contexts and sectors disseminated to policy-makers donors and practitioners; Strengthened expertise and capacity amongst member organisations and civil society partners to institutionalise and implement CSA at HQ and local levels. The project will focus in-depth on three countries (Kenya Sri Lanka and Sierra Leone) and will address one rapid onset emergency that may be elsewhere. It will seek to complement efforts by DFID to promote conflict sensitivity and envisages working in partnership with DFID on some advocacy activities. It will harness collective experience from development multi-mandate and peacebuilding NGOs to document best practice in CSA build capacity at institutional level and field levels share learning across broad networks and influence policies and practices of donors and other NGOs.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSC Consortium Proposal_July 2008.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[5]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[5]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/care-csa-pilot-capacity-building-workshop-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CARE CSA Pilot Capacity Building Workshop Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The goal of this three-year project is to introduce innovative agricultural practices that are more productive and more environmentally sustainable benefiting 11000 people including all land users and marginalized groups in 40 communities in Koinadugu district. This will be achieved through three specific objectives shown below with their correspondent outputs. Objective 1: Increase the adoption of sustainable agricultural practices by 11000 people in 40 communities in order to increase productivity and incomes through environmentally friendly use of land. Output 1.1: Expose 3000 farmers to conservation farming practices through establishment of 40 demonstration plots; Output 1.2: Improve animal husbandry through access to veterinary services for 120 livestock farmers and animal feed establishment of 20 fish ponds and improvement of beekeeping practices for 20 farmers. Objective 2: Improve the social and economic position of women and other marginalized groups (e.g. youth) by fully and directly involving them in agricultural development. Output 2.1: Assist 40 women’s groups in the establishment of profitable fruit and vegetable processing enterprises; Output 2.2: Assist 500 youth (members of FFS and VSLA) in getting sustainable access to the inputs and technical skills necessary to increase agricultural productivity and value addition. Objective 3: Establish land use agreements for marginalized groups including women livestock farmers immigrants and youth Output 3.1: Improve long term access to land for women and other marginalized groups Output 3.2: Prevent and mitigate land conflicts related to gender and ethnicity]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CARE CSA PILOT CAPACITY BUILDING WORKSHOP REPORT.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[6]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[6]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/slrcs-caps-pilot-fact-sheet]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[SLRCS CAPS Pilot Fact Sheet]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The overall goal of the CAPS project is "A culture of non violence justice and sustainable development is promoted in selected priority vulnerable communities”. Objective 1 Increase in community cohesion and family ties and the ability of communities to resolve conflict. Objective 2 Improve food security practice in targeted communities. Objective 3 Increase access and use of clean water and general hygiene practices improved in targeted communities]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CAPS FACT SHEET.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[7]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[7]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/care-conflict-sensitivity-launching-report-cap-project-kabala]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CARE Conflict Sensitivity Launching Report: CAP Project - Kabala]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The project is piloted through the implementation phase of the Howard Buffet sponsored Conservation Agriculture project implemented by CARE international in Sierra Leone in partnership with The Future in Our Hands(FIOH –local partner)in Kabala. On the 23 rd September 2010 this pilot project was officially launched in the Koinadugu district head quarter town of Kabala. Hundred persons drawn from all walks of life participated in the launching including representatives from international and local non governmental organizations (CRS CAUSE Canada Sierra Leone Red cross society PAGE FIOH ENCISS to name a few) Ministry of agriculture forestry and food security (MAFFS) the Sierra Leone police local leaders (paramount chiefs mammy queens youth leaders) Farmer Field School representatives CAP project participants and representatives of the Koinadugu District Council. The launching was particularly important as it marked the official kickoff of the pilot implementation to a wider audience. The CS program Coordinator Fred Goba vividly informed participants on the importance of the conflict sensitivity approach in the development and humanitarian effort and its impact in relation to the achievement of project goals across a wide range of development initiatives. The program was chaired by the representative of the host paramount chief of the Wara Wara Yagala Chiefdom. Participants gave various speeches following the introduction of the CS Project by the point person for the CS Programme in the CAP project-Edward Sophie. Key among the speech was that they are willing to embrace this type of programmes as it ensures a culture of transparency and accountability within and among development workers and project beneficiaries. And also ensures that project participants and other stakeholders are more involved in all phases of the project from planning to evaluation and they can take responsibility of success or failure without casting blames on others. Deliberations from participants were aired through the local radio in Kabala for the audience of the entire district. Further more the CS brochure was shared among participants present for the launching. The major challenge was the willingness of the district council staff to participate in the launching which serves as one key conflict sensitive indicator for the Programme to follow-up during the implementation.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CS LAUNCHING REPORT 2010.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[8]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[8]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/annex-3-conflict-sensitivity-emergency-response]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Annex 3: Conflict Sensitivity in Emergency Response]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This guide has some good examples of the value of applying CSA in emergencies drawing on case studies presented in the annexes. The document also provides valuable guidance with regard to emergency preparedness and for organisations involved in emergencies to ensure that response staff are trained in and able to use CSA in humanitarian and emergency work. However that guide also has limitations which the consortium has recognised and is addressing. The following strategy aims to enable the consortium to assist emergency response and humanitarian staff to practically apply conflict sensitive approaches in planning preparedness and interventions.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[ANNEX 3_CSA in Emergency Response_Oct 2010.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[9]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[9]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conducting-joint-conflict-analysis-process-kenya-consortium]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conducting Joint Conflict Analysis Process: Kenya Consortium]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : CONDUCTING JOINT CONFLICT ANALYSIS PROCESS Oct 09.pdf]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CONDUCTING JOINT CONFLICT ANALYSIS PROCESS Oct 09.pdf; CONDUCTING JOINT CONFLICT ANALYSIS PROCESS Oct 09.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[10]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[10]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-emergency-response-guide-practical-steps-first-30-days]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity in Emergency Response Guide: Practical steps for the first 30 days]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This guide Conflict Sensitivity in Emergency Response – practical steps for the first 30 days has been developed as a part of the pilot phase for the DFID CHF funded consortium project The practice of conflict sensitivity – concept to impact. The conflict sensitivity consortium is formed of 10 international NGOs: ActionAid; CAFOD; CARE International UK; International Alert; Plan International; Responding to Conflict; Saferworld; Save the Children UK; Skillshare International; and Worldvision. The objective of the guide is to provide international emergency humanitarian teams with a set of practical conflict sensitive approaches (CSA) that will help improve the conflict sensitivity of their work during the first 30 days of an emergency response.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CS IN EMERGENCY GUIDE.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[11]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[11]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-%E2%80%93-concept-impact-1st-narrative-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict-Sensitivity – Concept to Impact 1st Narrative Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS Basic Data Sheet Basic Data Sheet: Finances Key Results for Period according to Output/Planned Activity Project Logframe Emerging Impact at Output and Purpose Level Lessons Learnt Project Management Issues Flagged Issues Risk Assessment]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[1st CSC Narrative Report Jan 2009.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[12]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[12]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/csa-desk-research-sierra-leone]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CSA Desk Research in Sierra Leone]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The report is divided into four broad sections. Section one focuses on the causes of conflict in Sierra Leone while section two identifies key problem areas as well as stakeholders/actors. Section three presents the dynamics of conflict in Sierra Leone. In section four a review of available literature/research on conflict in Sierra Leone is presented. The section also depicts the main foci of current researchers the methodologies employed and gaps in ongoing research. Admittedly this desk research does not provide an exhaustive appraisal of conflict in Sierra Leone. Consequently members of the Sierra Leone's CSA consortium are advised to take liberties to supply any information they consider relevant to deepening our understanding of the trajectory of conflict in Sierra Leone during the conflict mapping workshop. This is essential as it provides the enabling environment for generating common understanding between and amongst consortium members on key conflict issues in the country.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[THE CSA DESK RESEARCH March 10.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[13]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[13]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/annual-cross-learning-workshop-conflict-sensitivity-consortium-report-proceedings]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Annual Cross-Learning Workshop for the Conflict Sensitivity Consortium: A Report of Proceedings]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Workshop topics: Sharing updates Institutional capacity analysis Pilots and Monitoring and Evaluation of pilots Advocacy Conflict Analysis Sharing in real time Evaluation]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSC ANNUAL EVENT REPORT Mombasa 2010.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[14]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[14]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-kenya-beyond-concept-documentation-case-studies]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict Sensitivity in Kenya: Beyond the Concept A Documentation of Case Studies]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This report captures the outcome of document review of case studies on conflict sensitive practice in Kenya and a series of self-assessment exercises among members of the Kenyan Conflict Sensitivity Consortium (CSC). In executing this mandate the process was initially guided by the definition of conflict sensitive approaches (CSA) as contained in the UK Conflict Sensitivity Consortium Benchmarking Paper: A conflict sensitive approach involves gaining a sound understanding of the two-way interaction between activities and context and acting to minimise negative impacts and maximise positive impacts of interventions on conflict within an organisation’s given priorities/objectives (mandate). Ultimately as will later be highlighted the Kenyan CSC adopted their definition of conflict sensitivity. This report is therefore a culmination of a reflective process that has been helpful in highlighting areas of improvement and/or fine-tuning for members’ conflict sensitive policies and practices. The main objectives of this exercise were: a. Document case studies on conflict sensitive practice b. Facilitate self-assessment exercises among consortium members c. Propose a unified/integrated conflict sensitivity assessment tool These three broad objectives inform the structure of this report.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Beyond the Concept A documentation of case studies.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[15]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[15]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-practitioners-training-manual]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity Practitioners' Training Manual]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This manual is intended for development humanitarian and peace practitioners it also applies to diplomatic governmental and donor agencies in identifying possible areas for infusion of conflict sensitivity. The manual is ideally useful as a guide for operationalisation of conflict sensitivity by way of assessments context analysis and mainstreaming of conflict sensitive approaches in institutional policies organisational interventions; community based initiatives individuals’ daily work and life settings but especially in conflict prone/affected zones. The realisation that assistance becomes part and parcel of the context and the conflict in the setting in which it is given makes it paramount for the people working in such scenarios to be able to understand the interaction between their actions and processes with the conflict dynamics in the context. This guiding manual is aimed at improving and enhancing the values and principles in the understanding application and monitoring of conflict-sensitive programming. It is intended to equip practitioners with skills and knowledge that will enable them to among other tasks conduct conflict sensitive trainings conflict analysis undertake peace and conflict impact assessments as well as to design implement monitor and evaluate conflict sensitive programs. It is designed for institutions and individuals who wish to ensure that the impact of their engagement will as a minimum ‘do no harm’ and as an optimum have a positive effect on the conflict areas in which the interventions are carried out. Institutional mandates and policies should therefore deliberately be designed to take into account the realities in conflict contexts to support peace and avoid exacerbating the tensions. This resource will help practitioners both in their personal life and in their work with communities.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSA Consortium Practitioners Manual.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[16]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[16]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/slrcs-conflict-sensitivity-launching-report-caps-project-pujehun]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[SLRCS Conflict Sensitivity Launching Report: CAPS Project - Pujehun]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Based on series of monitoring trips and assessments carried out by a team of consortium members on CAPS activities in Pujehun findings showed that the project is worthwhile for the launch of a CSA pilot project. The main goal of the pilot is to field test the application of CS approaches at project implementation level. The pilot project staff will also capitalize on this opportunity to improve on advocacy in minimizing the causes of conflict through the identification of Early Warning Signs in the communities.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CAPS Project Launch Report.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[17]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[17]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-capacity-self-assessments]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity Capacity Self-Assessments]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[In 2009 and 2010 member agencies of the Conflict Sensitivity Consortium undertook Conflict Sensitivity Capacity Self-Assessments. The aim of these self-assessments was to help member agencies to identify strengths weakness opportunities and blockages in terms of each agency’s capacity for conflict sensitivity. A variety of tools were utilized for the self-assessment – each agency and country started with a common framework/tool (developed by the consortium in early 2009) and adapted this tool according to individual agency or country need. Some agencies followed the original tool some refined the tool into a questionnaire and others simplified the original tool into more flexible and broader lines of inquiry. Likewise a variety of methodologies were followed – In the UK where the assessment was conducted first agencies were paired up and provided each other with peer support for the actual self-assessment. In other countries consultants supported and helped facilitate the process. The self-assessment included use of questionnaires focus group discussions targeted interviews as well as review of relevant agency documents. Despite following different tools and methodologies each agency ensured that their selfassessment covered a wide range of issues and stretched across a broad cross-section of the organisation encompassing departments beyond those actually implementing programming. The following are nine common sectors: 1. Coordination and programme support 2. Policies strategies & risk management 3. Design monitoring & evaluation 4. Communication documentation and information technology (IT) 5. Human Resource 6. Administration finance & Audit 7. Grants fundraising & sponsorships 8. Operations & partnerships Each agency documented both the process of their self-assessment and their key findings (documents that are available internally within the consortium). The next step was to share self-assessment findings across each country (Kenya Sierra Leone Sri Lanka UK). Each country held a review meeting to share findings across agencies to discuss next steps and to define change objectives. In the UK this workshop took place in July 2009 and in Sierra Leone Sri Lanka and Kenya it was held between August 2009 and early 2010. Each country discussed and developed consolidated potential change objectives which were taken back to each individual agency for further refinement. By the end of the second year of the consortium (March 2010) each consortium agency had developed (and secured agency internal buy-in) to a list of priority change objectives for working towards over the remaining two years of the consortium project. Recent progress updates from each country/agency are summarized in a separate annex.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Self-Assessment on CS_CSC Findings Overview 2010.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[18]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[18]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-consortium-benchmarking-paper-full-version]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity Consortium Benchmarking Paper-full version]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This paper was developed by members of the Conflict Sensitivity Consortium in the inception phase of the DFID-funded project “Conflict Sensitivity – Concept to Impact”. This paper seeks to set out the different interpretations of the concept of conflict sensitivity in order to provoke discussion amongst the consortium members and build consensus. This is to provide a solid foundation upon which future consortium work will be built to improve practice in conflict sensitivity.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity Benchmarking Paper April 09.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[19]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[19]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/annex-5-monitoring-report-agencies%E2%80%99-progress-and-plans]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Annex 5: Monitoring Report of Agencies’ Progress and Plans]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[During FY02 (April 2009-March 2010) all Consortium agencies in the UK Sri Lanka Sierra Leone and Kenya completed self-assessments to review the level of integration of conflict-sensitive principles and approaches into their organisational systems and identify main blockages and opportunities. Each agency then developed change objectives to pursue during FY03 and FY04 (see Annex 4: Summary of Self-Assessment Findings). This report provides an overview of the main achievements and progress to over the past two quarters for agencies in the UK consortium and in the Sri Lanka consortium as well as an indication of their most significant upcoming plans and a few highlighted key challenges. Progress is also underway in Kenya and Sierra Leone although those countries are not yet implementing this reporting structure. In the next report all four countries will provide progress reports as per the below template.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[ANNEX 5_Monitoring of Agency Progress Reports_UK and SLa.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[20]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[20]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/care-csa-activity-update]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CARE CSA Activity Update]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The Conflict Sensitivity Approach (CSA) is implemented through the Conservation Agriculture Project (CAP) in Koinadugu District. Following the completion of project launching and capacity building workshop couple of activities was implemented in the CA project these include: Land access and conflict mitigation meeting Local convention on wood exploitation grazing  burning and conflict Women and youth support in VSLA The conservation agriculture project is based on increasing productivity through sustainable land use i.e. moving from shifting cultivation to permanent stay on a piece of land year in –year out. This system therefore requires individuals or groups to access/own land for a long period of time. Also the project is implemented in an environment of alarming conflict between cattle farmers and crop farmers. Based on the above therefore the project is faced with two major challenges: firstly whilst the project is trying to mitigate conflict between cattle farmers and crop farmers the local leaders who are directly benefiting from the conflict are not providing the necessary support needed; this is making the situation more difficult. Secondly as the project push for long term access or permanent ownership of land for youths marginalized groups especially women and youths are not favored by the customary laws of Sierra Leone to have full access and control over productive asset like land. With respect to conflict sensitivity the project is therefore challenged to ensure peaceful prevention and mitigation of these conflicts and advocating for long term access to land for women and youth without creating more conflict in the operating environment. To ensure this the project uses the following strategies Interface local leaders with crop farmers and cattle farmers MAFFS and local council for long term access to land and conflict mitigation and the development of land use agreement Ensuring tree crop for women and youths to establish tree crop plantation Local convention on land use uncontrolled grazing and uncontrolled burning Women and youth support in VSLA These activities are on-going the conflict are reducing to some extent and some women have started establishing tree crops farm though there is no concrete agreement for the land to ensure tenure of security]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSA ACTIVITY UPDATE OCTOBER 2010.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[21]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[21]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/annex-2-learning-strategy]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Annex 2: Learning Strategy]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The Learning strategy has been developed to provide guidance across the four countries and will enable the Consortium to remain focused and reflect review and monitor more systematically whether the project is reaching its potential. The Consortium’s Mid‐Term Evaluation completed in March 2010 highlighted a number of findings and questions related to the project learning which have been taken into account to develop the strategy and will inform the monitoring of future Consortium’s progress in terms of transformative learning.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[ANNEX 2_Learning Strategy_October 2010.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[22]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[22]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/agency-self-assessment-process-and-findings-sierra-leone-consortium-abridged-versi]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Agency Self-Assessment Process and Findings: Sierra Leone Consortium (abridged version)]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Consortium member concerns were critical in developing the assessment methodology and subsequent tools. Such concerns also provided the opportunity for the consultants to clarify the reason for the agency self-assessments flag areas where there are opportunities for improvement without making agencies feel like being ‘evaluated’ (which agency has a more conflict sensitive approach). Feedback from some of the agencies visited suggests the process was interactive and empowering. A wide range of people including senior management mid-level and programme support staff participated in the agency self-assessment process.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Self-Assessment Process and FIndings_Sierra Leone_Abridged.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[23]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[23]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/care-cap-pilot-fact-sheet]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CARE CAP Pilot Fact Sheet]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : CAP Project Fact Sheet.doc]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CAP Project Fact Sheet.doc; CAP Project Fact Sheet.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[24]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[24]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/csa-logical-framework]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CSA Logical Framework]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : CSA Logical Framework 2009 Excel.pdf]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSA Logical Framework 2009 Excel.pdf; CSA Logical Framework 2009 Excel.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[25]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[25]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/annex-1-outreach-and-advocacy-strategy]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Annex 1: Outreach and Advocacy Strategy]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The following strategy outlines how the Consortium will share learning analysis and practical recommendations with peer agencies donors policy‐makers and other relevant stakeholders in‐country and in the UK. The strategy is intended to provide an evidence‐base to support country‐based staff and civil society partners to engage with policies of key donors/government around CSA in the focus countries and to influence the practices of development humanitarian and peacebuilding actors. It is deliberately light providing a broad framework that can accommodate context‐specific strategies in each of the focus countries for the CSA project (see details below). It is not intended as an overly technical or prescriptive strategy and it represents a shift from formal advocacy approaches which stress the ‘you should/you must’ to more informal engagement which creates learning opportunities and engenders debate about good practice at all levels. It is important to note that the project explicitly set out to “complement (and help shape) efforts by DfID to promote conflict sensitivity both internally and externally”.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[ANNEX 1_Outreach and Advocacy Strategy_Oct 2010.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[26]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[26]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/csa-context-analysis-presentation]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CSA Context Analysis Presentation]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : CSA CONTEXT ANALYSIS PRESENTATION March 10.pdf]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSA CONTEXT ANALYSIS PRESENTATION March 10.pdf; CSA CONTEXT ANALYSIS PRESENTATION March 10.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[27]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[27]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-%E2%80%93-concept-impact-4th-narrative-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict-Sensitivity – Concept to Impact 4th Narrative Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : 4th CSC Narrative Report April 2010.doc]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[4th CSC Narrative Report April 2010.doc; 4th CSC Narrative Report April 2010.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[28]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[28]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-emergency-response-guide-annex-2-additional-references]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity in Emergency Response Guide Annex 2: Additional References]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : Annex 2 - Additional References.pdf]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Annex 2 - Additional References.pdf; Annex 2 - Additional References.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[29]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[29]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitivity-consortium-benchmarking-paper-abridged-version]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity Consortium Benchmarking Paper - abridged version]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[In early 2009 at the start of the Project the UK Consortium produced a ‘Benchmarking Paper’ to build consensus and a common working definition of conflict sensitivity. In early 2010 the UK Consortium decided to produce an abridged version of the Benchmarking Paper that can more easily be shared with a wider audience and as a result this paper was developed.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitivity Benchmarking Paper_Short Version.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[30]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[30]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/slrcs-csa-pilot-capacity-building-workshop-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[SLRCS CSA Pilot Capacity Building Workshop Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[As a follow-up to the launch of the CSA Pilot Project CSA organized a capacity building workshop for SLRCS staff and their implementing partners in Pujehun in Southern Province on 5 th October 2010. The overall goal of the workshop was to enhance participants knowledge to be more conflict sensitive in the planning implementation and monitoring of projects they undertake. The workshop also sought to attention to some the consequences of lack of knowledge of conflict sensitivity on project implementers as well as recipients.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CAPS Capacity Building Report.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[31]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[31]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitive-approaches-analysis-kenyan-context]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitive Approaches: An Analysis of the Kenyan Context]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction and Methodology: A combination of the desk and field researches Desk Research: Sought to provide details of the key causes of conflict conflict dynamics and conflict actors in Kenya. A conflict mapping workshop: Aimed at identifying gaps and prioritising areas for further research. This informed the focus of the participatory conflict analysis Participatory conflict analysis: Focused on thematic areas/sectors informed by the mapping workshop as well as on the shared interests and areas of work of consortium members. The study involved actual field research stakeholder workshops and key informant interviews. Based on the Consortium’s intervention mapping exercise it was found that members worked in all of Kenya’s provinces except Central. The findings cover as a result those seven provinces (Coast North Eastern Rift Valley Nairobi Eastern Western and Nyanza).]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitive Approaches (Analysis findings).pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[32]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[32]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-%E2%80%93-concept-impact-5th-narrative-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict Sensitivity – Concept to Impact 5th Narrative Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : 5th Narrative Report_Conflict Sensitivity Consortium_October 2010.pdf]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[5th Narrative Report_Conflict Sensitivity Consortium_October 2010.pdf; 5th Narrative Report_Conflict Sensitivity Consortium_October 2010.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[33]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[33]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-%E2%80%93-concept-impact-2nd-narrative-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict-Sensitivity – Concept to Impact 2nd Narrative Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : 2nd CSC Narrative Report April 09.doc]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[2nd CSC Narrative Report April 09.doc; 2nd CSC Narrative Report April 09.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[34]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[34]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/conflict-sensitive-approaches-presentation]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Conflict Sensitive Approaches Presentation]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction to conflict sensitive approaches and discussion of conflict sensitive definition and issues]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Conflict sensitivity PRESENTATION.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[35]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[35]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/agency-self-assessment-process-and-findings-sierra-leone-consortium-full-version]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Agency Self-Assessment Process and Findings: Sierra Leone Consortium (full version)]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[The Sierra Leone Conflict Sensitivity Consortium which was managed by World Vision Sierra Leone comprises seven (7) agencies that encompass Humanitarian Development and Peace building work. Although consortium members were quite confused at the beginning regarding the concept of Conflict Sensitivity and at best had divergent views about what a conflict sensitive approach (CSA) entails for their respective agencies the self-assessment proved to be an important learning process. Despite variations in organizational mandates programme emphasis and capacity among consortium agencies the process helped to discover common trends among members with potential to mainstream CSA in Sierra Leone. After several debates about how member organizations viewed the definitions of CSA as indicated in the benchmark paper a near consensus was conceptualized that ‘conflict sensitive approach involves gaining a sound understanding of the two-way interaction between activities and context and acting [on such understanding] to minimize negative impacts and maximize positive impacts of interventions on conflict [and vice versa] of all programs and policies within an organization’s given priorities/objectives (mandate) was adopted. This definition was seen as the closest to the Sierra Leonean context and best aligned to existing literature experience and practice elsewhere. Consortium member concerns were critical in developing the assessment methodology and subsequent tools (see methodology below). Such concerns also provided the opportunity for the consultants to clarify the reason for the agency self-assessments flag areas where there are opportunities for improvement without making agencies feel like being ‘evaluated’ (which agency has a more conflict sensitive approach). Instead feedback from some of the agencies visited suggests the process was interactive and empowering. A wide range of people including senior management mid-level and programme support staff participated in the agency self-assessment process. Prior to the self-assessment exercise the consultants developed tools in the form of templates for documenting case studies and change objectives of agencies. These were validated at a pre-assessment workshop. While differences exist in terms of priorities and programme emphasis among consortium members the pre-assessment workshop helped to identify some organizational and operational commonalities among agencies. This was critical in determining the self-assessment depth and approach. The following are nine common sectors that cut across the seven consortium agencies: Coordination and programme support Policies strategies & risk management Community-based-programmes (youth food security WAS RBA) Design monitoring & evaluation Communication documentation and information technology (IT) Human Resource Administration finance & Audit Grants fundraising & sponsorships Operations & partnerships Meanwhile it is important to note that the consultants could not facilitate the self-assessment process on one of the agencies Plan Sierra Leone. The entire assessment process was also significantly constrained due to the time of year in which key personnel in many of the organizations were in the middle of developing new budgets. Nonetheless sufficient data was collected and analyzed using the following format: Review of relevant agency documents ( e.g. strategic framework / papers incident reports policies MoUs ) to inform agency CSA Practices Discussion with agency staff in all nine sectors (e.g. HR Programmes Procurement DM&E etc) Use of sector-related questionnaire One-on-one interviews with sector personnel Exploring sector understanding experience & definition of CSA Pulling together in a plenary various sector findings experiences & definitions of CSA. Compilation of Agency CSA best practices and Case Studies Findings regarding the whole process have been categorized into three levels: Agency Level – Change objectives which are to be worked on by specific agencies Consortium Level – Change Objectives which are to be worked on collectively at consortium level Joint Learning - Findings considered as CSA best practices (Exit interviews practiced by CAFOD and an Open information policy practiced by ACTION AID). The two agencies were identified to lead in sharing such experiences with the rest of the consortium members. In order to demonstrate how consortium members have understood the concept of CSA and the reasons why agencies have preferred the first benchmark position as the nearest context-specific definition of CSA for Sierra Leone some specific scenario-based experiences were documented as case studies during the assessment as recorded in section eight (8) of this report. These are expected to serve as possible future action points and shared learning pointers among consortium members.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Self-Assessment Process and FIndings_Sierra Leone_full.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[36]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[36]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/csa-pilot-project-activities-maralal-project]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[CSA Pilot Project Activities: Maralal Project]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Project Title: Integrated Peace and Livelihood Project Goal: Household food security enhanced through increased incomes and communities capacities for peace conflict transformation and demand for justice enhanced among communities in Maralal Diocese Project Output: Enhanced and strengthened peace and harmony among different communities Increased household incomes through enhanced access to markets improved livestock breeds and increased access to capital for income generation activities and livestock marketing]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[CSA Pilot project activities -Maralal Project (2).pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[37]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[37]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/annex-4-conflict-sensitivity-capacity-self-assessments]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Annex 4: Conflict Sensitivity Capacity Self-Assessments]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[In 2009 and 2010 member agencies of the Conflict Sensitivity Consortium undertook Conflict Sensitivity Capacity Self-Assessments. The aim of these self-assessments was to help member agencies to identify strengths weakness opportunities and blockages in terms of each agency’s capacity for conflict sensitivity. A variety of tools were utilized for the self-assessment – each agency and country started with a common framework/tool (developed by the consortium in early 2009) and adapted this tool according to individual agency or country need. Some agencies followed the original tool some refined the tool into a questionnaire and others simplified the original tool into more flexible and broader lines of inquiry. Likewise a variety of methodologies were followed – In the UK where the assessment was conducted first agencies were paired up and provided each other with peer support for the actual self-assessment. In other countries consultants supported and helped facilitate the process. The self-assessment included use of questionnaires focus group discussions targeted interviews as well as review of relevant agency documents. Despite following different tools and methodologies each agency ensured that their self-assessment covered a wide range of issues and stretched across a broad cross-section of the organisation encompassing departments beyond those actually implementing programming. The following are nine common sectors: 1. Coordination and programme support 2. Policies strategies & risk management 3. Design monitoring & evaluation 4. Communication documentation and information technology (IT) 5. Human Resource 6. Administration finance & Audit 7. Grants fundraising & sponsorships 8. Operations & partnerships Each agency documented both the process of their self-assessment and their key findings (documents that are available internally within the consortium). The next step was to share self-assessment findings across each country (Kenya Sierra Leone Sri Lanka UK). Each country held a review meeting to share findings across agencies to discuss next steps and to define change objectives. In the UK this workshop took place in July 2009 and in Sierra Leone Sri Lanka and Kenya it was held between August 2009 and early 2010. Each country discussed and developed consolidated potential change objectives which were taken back to each individual agency for further refinement. By the end of the second year of the consortium (March 2010) each consortium agency had developed (and secured agency internal buy-in) to a list of priority change objectives for working towards over the remaining two years of the consortium project. Recent progress updates from each country/agency are summarized in a separate annex.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[ANNEX 4_Findings and Lessons Learnt from Self-Assessment Process.doc.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[38]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[38]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/practice-conflict-sensitivity-%E2%80%93-concept-impact-3rd-narrative-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[The Practice of Conflict-Sensitivity – Concept to Impact 3rd Narrative Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[Download : 3rd CSC Narrative Report Oct 09.doc]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[3rd CSC Narrative Report Oct 09.doc; 3rd CSC Narrative Report Oct 09.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[39]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[39]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/terms-reference-pilot-conflict-sensitivity-approaches-project-implementation-level]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Terms of Reference To pilot Conflict Sensitivity Approaches at Project Implementation Level]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[This element of the CSA project will focus on how conflict sensitivity is applied during project implementation phase. This CS pilot project is not generated or implemented to correct errors in the selected project. Instead the pilot will aim at improving the conflict sensitivity of selected consortium partner projects. It will also look at the project and develop and demonstrate effectiveness of conflict sensitivity; or it will present the added value of conflict sensitivity. The Sierra Leone consortium will adapt the following methodology: Identify two consortium agency projects in contextually distinct regions and as informed by the conflict mapping workshop. Ensure the Identified projects are ongoing and directly implemented by a consortium member agency. Undertake a project analysis of the proposed pilots during the conflict /context analysis. Regularly update the project and conflict/context analysis. This methodology will provide sufficient lessons for development of effective Conflict Sensitivity (CS) case studies and provide a guide on adjustments / adaptations to be undertaken.]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[20101018 ToR Implementation Pilots.doc]]></pdf>
	</node>
	<node>
		<_input><![CDATA[]]></_input>
		<_num><![CDATA[40]]></_num>
		<_widgetname><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_widgetname>
		<_source><![CDATA[consortium publications crawler pt.1]]></_source>
		<_resultnumber><![CDATA[40]]></_resultnumber>
		<_pageurl><![CDATA[http://www.conflictsensitivity.org/internaldocuments/kenya-conflict-analysis-summary-report]]></_pageurl>
		<title><![CDATA[Kenya Conflict Analysis Summary Report]]></title>
		<description><![CDATA[There are a number of contextual realities that define and constitute the key driving factors of Kenya’s conflicts as pointed out in this conflict analysis report: Identity consciousness and politics Resource scarcity and competition for it Governance issues and clamour for better governance Illicit small arms flows and possession Organised gangs warriors and militias]]></description>
		<pdf><![CDATA[Kenya Conflict Analysis SUMMARY REPORT.pdf]]></pdf>
	</node>
</data>
